Have you ever taken a taxi?
你坐过出租车吗？
In the past, doing so meant finding one, flagging it down and telling the driver where you wanted to go, paying, and possibly, adding a tip.
在过去，坐出租车意味着要找到一辆车，挥手拦下（flagging down），然后告诉司机你要去的地方，付款，而且可能还要给小费。
And while this still happens, it’s less common than it used to be.
虽然这种情况仍然存在，但不像过去那么常见了。
These days, it’s much easier to open a ride-hailing app.
如今，打开一个叫车应用程序要容易得多。
All of the boring stuff gets taken care of.
所有那些麻烦的事情都有人处理。
It’s a perfect solution!
这似乎是个完美的解决方案！
Except that it isn’t.
只可惜事实并非如此。
A recent report from urban transport consultant Bruce Schaller, who spent the last four years studying traffic flow in New York, concluded that the use of these app-based journeys is causing traffic jams.
城市交通顾问布鲁斯・沙勒（Bruce Schaller）在过去四年里一直在研究纽约的交通流量，他在最近的一份报告中得出结论，使用这些基于应用程序的出行方式正在造成交通拥堵。
The 81% increase in these city-based rides means that there are now five times more of them than the iconic yellow taxicab.
这些通过应用程序叫车的城市出行次数增加了81%，这意味着现在这类出行的数量是标志性的黄色出租车的五倍。
“It’s the shift in patronage from public transport,” he told the BBC.
“人们不再使用（惠顾）公共交通，”他告诉英国广播公司（BBC）。
For whatever reason, people decide that it’s just too much hassle.
不管出于什么原因，人们认为乘坐公共交通太麻烦了。
“That means moving people from larger vehicles into smaller ones, which means more vehicles to move the same people.
“这意味着人们从大型交通工具转向小型交通工具，也就意味着需要更多的车辆来运送同样数量的人。
Therefore, more traffic.”
因此，交通会更加拥堵。”
In addition, the sheer number of cars now looking for a commuter means that they spend 45% of their time empty, just cruising for a fare, and inadvertently clogging up the city’s infrastructure.
此外，现在大量的汽车在寻找通勤乘客，这意味着它们45%的时间都是空车，只是在巡游揽客，并且在不经意间堵塞了城市的基础设施。
“They are out there in force at the worst possible times,” said Prof Christo Wilson, a computer scientist at Northeastern University, who has also studied the services.
“它们在最糟糕的时候大量出现，”东北大学（Northeastern University）的计算机科学家克里斯托・威尔逊（Christo Wilson）教授说，他也在研究这些出行服务。
He refers to Uber’s traffic data, which ‘perfectly matches the peaks for the rush hour.’
他提到优步（Uber）的交通数据，这些数据“与高峰时段的流量高峰完美匹配”。
He also adds that the low fares and convenience mean that people are ordering rides to go from A to B when they wouldn’t normally.
他还补充说，低廉的票价和便利性意味着人们在平时不会打车的时候也会叫车从A地前往B地。
Both help contribute to the gridlock.
这两个因素都导致了交通堵塞。
So what can be done to stop traffic from backing up or bottlenecking?
那么，要怎么做才能阻止出现交通堵塞或瓶颈呢？
One solution involves combining ride-hailing with sharing.
一个解决方案是将叫车服务与拼车相结合。
Many ride-hailing companies, such as Uber, Didi Chuxing in China and Ola in India enable customers to carpool.
许多叫车公司，比如优步、中国的滴滴出行和印度的奥拉（Ola），都让客户可以拼车。
This allows travellers who share similar destinations to share the journey.
这使得有相似目的地的旅客可以共享行程。
The app enables an en route pickup, which means more streamlined traffic, and less time spent with an empty vehicle.
应用程序支持途中接客，这意味着更加顺畅（流线型）的交通，空车行驶的时间也更少。
Could this decongest the world’s jam-packed roads?
这能疏通世界上拥堵不堪的道路吗？
It is certainly one solution.
这当然是一个解决方案。
But maybe we shouldn’t be so quick to dismiss the more traditional public transport options.
但也许我们不应该这么快就否定更传统的公共交通选择。
"Congestion is a really complicated issue," said Andrew Salzberg, head of Uber's transport policy.
优步交通政策负责人安德鲁・萨尔茨伯格（Andrew Salzberg）说：“交通拥堵是一个非常复杂的问题。”
But, “There is no more efficient way to move people around than public transport," he added.
但是，“没有比公共交通更有效的运送人们的方式了，”他补充道。
So don’t do away with that bus pass just yet.
所以，先别扔掉你的公交卡。